<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Phase 1 on psc's website</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/</link><description>Recent content in Phase 1 on psc's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Episode 5: Repeats &amp; Loops</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode5/</guid><description>The code for this episode is available here.
Loops are such an essential part of programming that I knew I&amp;rsquo;d have to make an episode on them at some point. A natural musical analogue is musical repeats, so the whole episode came fairly naturally!
I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to have some beats to accompany the piano, so I used SuperCollider for that. That proved to be the most challenging part of the episode, as getting the timing right was really hard.</description></item><item><title>Episode 4: Live Coding &amp; Jazz</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode4/</guid><description>The code for this episode is available here.
I had a different idea for the fourth episode, but then I saw John McLaughlin&amp;rsquo;s tweet about International Jazz day, and decided to do something for that instead.
Obviously I&amp;rsquo;d talk about Jazz in the musical section, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear yet what part of Jazz I&amp;rsquo;d talk about. I spoke to a few people and it seemed like a good idea would be to talk about improvisation, and how jazz musicians do it; in particular, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this helps people who don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; jazz to understand what we&amp;rsquo;re doing when we play it, and that we&amp;rsquo;re not just playing random notes!</description></item><item><title>Episode 3: Leitmotifs &amp; Variables</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode3/</guid><description>The code for this episode is available here.
I had it in my head that the third episode would talk about variables in the section about Computer Science. Originally I thought the musical would be about chords, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit well with variables. Then I thought about key signatures, thinking that these are kind of like variables in the sense that you can shift any song into different pitches just by changing key signatures; but again, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very content with the connection.</description></item><item><title>Episode 2: Bits &amp; Semitones</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode2/</guid><description>The code for this episode is available here.
The idea for doing something with bits seemed kind of natural to me as a second episode. After covering what &amp;ldquo;computation&amp;rdquo; is, why not cover what computers actually &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; when they run computations?
Given that bits are what makes up everything inside a computer&amp;rsquo;s software, I wanted a musical topic that was inside every type of music (at least in Western music).</description></item><item><title>Episode 1: Musical Notes &amp; Computation</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/episode1/</guid><description>The code for this episode is available here.
I originally thought this channel would be a kind of educational channel, where people could learn about both music and computer science in a fun and informal way. I tweeted asking for suggestions for what to cover first on the CS side, and Kory Mathewson&amp;rsquo;s response was my favourite.
On the music side, it was kind of a train-of-thought process. The first thing that came to mind when thinking about the first thing you might learn in music theory was musical notes themselves.</description></item><item><title>Introducing MUSICODE</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/introducing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/musicode/phase1/introducing/</guid><description>A musical ode to musical code.
Subscribe to the YouTube channel!.
Each episode will explore a topic in Computer Science, a topic in Music, and combine them in creative ways.
You can find the code I use for each episode here!
The story The reason I decided to start this show was because, thanks to COVID-19, I was no longer performing live with my jazz trio, but I was aching for some type of performative output.</description></item></channel></rss>