<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mentoring / Education on psc's website</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/</link><description>Recent content in Mentoring / Education on psc's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to reinforcement learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/intro-to-rl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/intro-to-rl/</guid><description>This post is based on this colab.
You can also watch a video where I go through the basics here.
Pueden ver un video (en español) donde presento el material aquí.
Introduction Reinforcement learning methods are used for sequential decision making in uncertain environments. It is typically framed as an agent (the learner) interacting with an environment which provides the agent with reinforcement (positive or negative), based on the agent&amp;rsquo;s decisions.</description></item><item><title>GridWorld Playground</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/gridworldplayground/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/gridworldplayground/</guid><description>GridWorld playground!
I made a website where you can
Draw your own GridWorlds Play around with hyperparameters while agent is training Transfer values between agents &amp;ldquo;Teleport&amp;rdquo; the agent to help it during learning Hope you find it useful and fun!</description></item><item><title>Tips for Interviewing at Google</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/interviewing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/interviewing/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This post reflects my personal views and not those of my employer.
People often ask me: How do I get a job at Google?
An essential requirement is passing the interviews; unsurprisingly, this is another common question: How do I pass the Google interviews?
While there is no hard and fast rule to pass the Google interviews, I do have some tips and guidelines that have helped others in the past (including myself).</description></item><item><title>Tips for preparing your resume</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/mentoring/resume/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This post reflects my personal views and not those of my employer.
In my previous post providing tips for interviewing at Google, I included the sentence “If you don’t know anyone at Google, you’ve already applied and haven’t heard back in a while, feel free to send me a note with your CV and I’ll see if there’s something I can do.”
I received a number of requests from people who had applied but never heard back.</description></item></channel></rss>