<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reinforcement Learning on psc's website</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/</link><description>Recent content in Reinforcement Learning on psc's website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In Defense of Atari - the ALE is not 'solved'!</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/atari_defense/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/atari_defense/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is based on a talk I gave at the &lt;a href="https://autorlworkshop.github.io/">AutoRL workshop in ICML 2024&lt;/a>, which unfortunately was not recorded.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Reinforcement Learning (RL) has been used successfully in a number of challenging tasks, such as &lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/research/breakthroughs/alphago/">beating world champions at Go&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-04301-9">controlling tokamak plasmas for nuclear fusion&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03544-w">optimized chip placement&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2939-8">controlling stratospheric balloons&lt;/a>. All these successes have leveraged years of research and expertise and, importantly, rely on the combination of RL algorithms with deep neural networks (as proposed in the seminal &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature14236">DQN paper&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From "Bigger, Better, Faster" to "Smaller, Sparser, Stranger"</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/from_bbf_to_sss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/from_bbf_to_sss/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a post based on a talk I gave a few times in 2023. I had been meaning to put it in blog post form for over a year but kept putting it off&amp;hellip; I guess better late than never. I think some of the ideas still hold, so hope some of you find it useful!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bigger-better-faster">Bigger, better, faster&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature14236">seminal DQN paper&lt;/a>, Mnih et al. demonstrated that reinforcement learning, when combined with neural networks as function approximators, could learn to play Atari 2600 games at superhuman levels. The DQN agent learned to do this over 200 million environment frames, which is roughly equivalent to 1000 hours of human gameplay&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dormant Neuron Phenomenon in Deep Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/redo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/redo/</guid><description>&lt;p>We identify the dormant neuron phenomenon in deep reinforcement learning, where an agent&amp;rsquo;s network suffers from an increasing number of inactive neurons, thereby affecting network expressivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Ghada Sokar, Rishabh Agarwal, Pablo Samuel Castro*, Utku Evci*&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This blogpost is a summary of our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12902">ICML 2023 paper&lt;/a>.
The code is available
&lt;a href="https://github.com/google/dopamine/tree/master/dopamine/labs/redo">here&lt;/a>.
Many more results and analyses are available in the paper, so I encouraged you to
check it out if interested!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following figure gives a nice summary of the overall findings of our work
(we are reporting the Interquantile Mean (IQM) as introduced in
&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.13264">our Statistical Precipice NeurIPS'21 paper&lt;/a>):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Th State of Spars Train ng in D ep Re nforc m nt Le rn ng</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/sparse_rl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/sparse_rl/</guid><description>&lt;p>We perform a systematic investigation into applying a number of existing sparse
training techniques on a variety of deep RL agents and environments, and
conclude by suggesting promising avenues for improving the effectiveness of
sparse training methods, as well as for advancing their use in DRL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Laura Graesser*, Utku Evci*, Erich Elsen, Pablo Samuel Castro&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This blogpost is a summary of our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10369">ICML 2022 paper&lt;/a>.
The code is available
&lt;a href="https://github.com/google-research/rigl/tree/master/rigl/rl">here&lt;/a>.
Many more results and analyses are available in the paper, so I encouraged you to
check it out if interested!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Reinforcement Learning at the Edge of the Statistical Precipice</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/precipice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/precipice/</guid><description>&lt;p>We argue that reliable evaluation in the few run deep RL regime cannot ignore
the uncertainty in results without running the risk of slowing down progress in
the field. We illustrate this point using a case study on the Atari 100k
benchmark, where we find substantial discrepancies between conclusions drawn
from point estimates alone versus a more thorough statistical analysis.
We advocate for reporting interval estimates of aggregate performance and
propose performance profiles to account for the variability in results, as well
as present more robust and efficient aggregate metrics, such as interquartile
mean scores, to achieve small uncertainty in results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Difficulty of Passive Learning in Deep Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/tandem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/tandem/</guid><description>&lt;p>We propose the &amp;ldquo;tandem learning&amp;rdquo; experimental design, where two RL agents are
learning from identical data streams, but only one interacts with the
environment to collect the data. We use this experiment design to study the
empirical challenges of offline reinforcement learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Georg Ostrovski, Pablo Samuel Castro, Will Dabney&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This blogpost is a summary of our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.14020">NeurIPS 2021 paper&lt;/a>.
We provide two Tandem RL implementations:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/deepmind/deepmind-research/tree/master/tandem_dqn">this one&lt;/a>
based on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/deepmind/dqn_zoo">DQN Zoo&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="https://github.com/google/dopamine/tree/master/dopamine/labs/tandem_dqn">this one&lt;/a>
based on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/google/dopamine">Dopamine library&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MICo: Learning improved representations via sampling-based state similarity for Markov decision processes</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/mico/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/mico/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a new behavioural distance over the state space of a Markov
decision process, and demonstrate the use of this distance as an effective
means of shaping the learnt representations of deep reinforcement learning
agents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Pablo Samuel Castro*, Tyler Kastner*, Prakash Panangaden, and Mark Rowland&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;center>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CWKv2R30c9E" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/center>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This blogpost is a summary of our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.08229">NeurIPS 2021 paper&lt;/a>.
The code is available
&lt;a href="https://github.com/google-research/google-research/tree/master/mico">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following figure gives a nice summary of the empirical gains our new loss
provides, yielding an improvement on all of the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/google/dopamine">Dopamine&lt;/a> agents (left), as well as over Soft
Actor-Critic and the DBC algorithm of &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.10742">Zhang et al., ICLR 2021&lt;/a> (right).
In both cases we are reporting the Interquantile Mean as introduced in
&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.13264">our Statistical Precipice NeurIPS'21 paper&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revisiting Rainbow: Promoting more insightful and inclusive deep reinforcement learning research</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/revisiting_rainbow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/revisiting_rainbow/</guid><description>&lt;p>We argue for the value of small- to mid-scale environments in deep RL for increasing scientific insight and help make our community more inclusive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Johan S. Obando-Ceron and Pablo Samuel Castro&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a summary of our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.14826">paper&lt;/a> which was accepted at the
&lt;a href="https://icml.cc/">Thirty-eighth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML'21)&lt;/a>. (An initial version was presented at the &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/corp/view/deep-rl-workshop-neurips2020/home">deep reinforcement learning workshop at NeurIPS 2020&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The code is available &lt;a href="https://github.com/JohanSamir/revisiting_rainbow">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the Deep RL talk &lt;a href="https://slideslive.com/38941329/revisiting-rainbow-promoting-more-insightful-and-inclusive-deep-reinforcement-learning-research">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metrics and continuity in reinforcement learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/metrics_continuity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/metrics_continuity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this work we investigate the notion of &amp;ldquo;state similarity&amp;rdquo; in Markov decision processes. This concept is central to generalization in RL with function approximation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2102.01514">Our paper&lt;/a> was published at AAAI'21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Charline Le Lan, Marc G. Bellemare, and Pablo Samuel Castro&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The text below was adapted from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/charlinelelan/status/1357006401952972808">Charline&amp;rsquo;s twitter thread&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In RL, we often deal with systems with large state spaces. We can’t exactly represent the value of each of these states and need some type of generalization. One way to do that is to look at structured representations in which similar states are assigned similar predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contrastive Behavioral Similarity Embeddings for Generalization in Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/pse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/pse/</guid><description>&lt;p>This &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2101.05265">paper&lt;/a> was accepted as a spotlight at ICLR'21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose a new metric and contrastive loss that comes equipped with theoretical and empirical results.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/pse/jumpy.png"
 
 alt="Jumping task"
 
 
 width="50%"
 
 
 
 
 class="center"
 
>

&lt;h2 id="policy-similarity-metric">Policy Similarity Metric&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We introduce the policy similarity metric (PSM) which is based on &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1207.4114">bisimulation metrics&lt;/a>.
In contrast to bisimulation metrics (which is built on reward differences), PSMs are built on differences in optimal policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/pse/psm.png"
 
 alt="Policy similarity metric"
 
 
 width="80%"
 
 
 
 
 class="center"
 
>

&lt;p>If we were to use this metric for policy transfer (as Doina Precup &amp;amp; I &lt;a href="http://ojs.aaai.org/index.php/AAAI/article/view/7751">explored previously&lt;/a>), we can upper-bound the difference between the optimal and the transferred policy:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2020 RL highlights</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/2020highlights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/2020highlights/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of &lt;a href="https://twimlai.com/">TWiML&lt;/a> &amp;rsquo;s AI Rewind series, I was asked to provide a list of reinforcement learning papers that were highlights for me in 2020. It&amp;rsquo;s been a difficult year for pretty much everyone, but it&amp;rsquo;s heartening to see that despite all the difficulties, interesting research still came out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given the size and breadth of the reinforcement learning research, as well as the fact that I was asked to do this at the end of NeurIPS and right before my vacation, I decided to apply the following rules in the selection:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autonomous navigation of stratospheric balloons using reinforcement learning</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/loon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/loon/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this work we, quite literally, take reinforcement learning to new heights! Specifically, we use deep reinforcement learning to help control the navigation of stratospheric balloons, whose purpose is to deliver internet to areas with low connectivity. This project is an ongoing collaboration with &lt;a href="https://loon.com/">Loon&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly rewarding to see reinforcement learning deployed successfully in a real setting. It&amp;rsquo;s also been terrific to work alongside such fantastic co-authors:&lt;br>
&lt;em>Marc G. Bellemare, Salvatore Candido, Pablo Samuel Castro, Jun Gong, Marlos C. Machado, Subhodeep Moitra, Sameera S. Ponda, Ziyu Wang&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scalable methods for computing state similarity in deterministic MDPs</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/scalable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/scalable/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post describes my paper &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1911.09291">Scalable methods for computing state similarity in deterministic MDPs&lt;/a>, published at &lt;a href="https://aaai.org/Conferences/AAAI-20/">AAAI 2020&lt;/a>. The code is available &lt;a href="https://github.com/google-research/google-research/tree/master/bisimulation_aaai2020">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="motivation">Motivation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We consider distance metrics between states in an MDP. Take the following MDP, where the goal is to reach the green cells:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/scalable/sampleMDP.png"
 
 alt="Sample MDP"
 
 
 width="50%"
 
 
 
 
 class="center"
 
>

&lt;h3 id="physical-distance-betweent-states">Physical distance betweent states?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Physical distance often fails to capture the similarity properties we&amp;rsquo;d like:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/scalable/physicalDistance.png"
 
 alt="Physical distance"
 
 
 width="50%"
 
 
 
 
 class="center"
 
>

&lt;h3 id="state-abstractions">State abstractions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now imagine we add an exact copy of these states to the MDP (think of it as an additional &amp;ldquo;floor&amp;rdquo;):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dopamine: A framework for flexible value-based reinforcement learning research</title><link>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/dopamine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/dopamine/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/dopamine/dopamine.png"
 
 alt="Dopamine logo"
 
 
 
 
 
>

&lt;p>Dopamine is a framework for flexible, value-based, reinforcement learning research. It was originally written in TensorFlow, but now all agents have been implemented in JAX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read more about it in &lt;a href="https://github.com/google/dopamine">our github page&lt;/a> and in our &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.06110">white paper&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/08/introducing-new-framework-for-flexible.html">Original Google AI blogpost&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a website where you can easily compare the performance of all the Dopamine agents, which I find really useful:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://google.github.io/dopamine/baselines/plots.html">&lt;img src="https://psc-g.github.io/posts/research/rl/dopamine/baselines.png"
 
 alt="Baselines screenshot"
 
 
 
 
 
>
&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also provide a set of Colaboratory notebooks that really help understand the framework:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>